我们已经讲过几次，把sw写在
We mentioned this several times. Put the SW in
素材文件夹的名字里表示最小屏宽。
the resource folder name stands for smallest width. To drive
为了真正理解这一点，我们来看一个假设的情况。
home that point, let's walk through a hypothetical situation. Say
假设你有一个这样的文件夹结构。
you have an app directory structure like this. We have
在默认Layout文件夹里有一些配置文件
some layouts defined in the base layout folder and
其中一些被layout-sw600dp文件夹里的配置文件覆盖掉
we override some of those in the layout-sw600dp folder. We
其中一个又被layout-sw720dp文件夹的配置文件覆盖掉
also override one of these in the layout-sw720dp folder. Let's
我们来看看哪一个配置文件会被应用到哪一个设备上
look at which layouts would be applied on which device.
假设你的APP在Nexus 5上运行
Say your app is running on a Nexus five.
Nexus 5的大小是360dp*640dp
The Nexus five has dimensions 360 dp by six 640
在两个数字中，最小屏宽是360dp
dp. Of the two, the smallest width is 360 dp.
所以我们用这个数字来和文件夹名字
So we use this number to compare it against the
比较。360dp小于600dp
folder names. 360 dp is less than 600 and
也小于720dp。所以所有的配置文件
is less than 720 so all the layouts will come
会使用这个默认Layout文件夹里的。对于Nexus 7 2012的版本
from this base layout folder. For the Nexus 7 2012 version,
它的大小是600dp*960dp
the dimensions are 600 dp by 960 dp. Of the
这两个数字中600dp是最小屏宽。所以用它
two sides 600 dp is the smaller width. So you compare
和文件夹名字比较。很明显它的最小屏宽
this against the folder names. It turns out that the smallest width
大于等于600dp。所以
is greater than or equal to 600 dp, so for the
detail和item这两个配置文件会使用这个文件夹里的。
detail and the item layout, we pull it from this folder. Now
这个文件夹里没有main.xml
the main .xml file is not declared in this folder, so
所以我们退回较小限制的文件夹，也就是
we fall back to a less specific folder, which turns out to
这一个默认Layout文件夹。对于Nexus 10
be this one in the base layout folder. For the Nexus ten,
它的大小是800dp*1280dp。这两个数字中，
the dimensions are 800 dp by 1280 dp. Of the two sides,
800dp是最小屏宽。这个设备满足
800 dp is the smallest width. Now this device satisfies
所有这些分类。因为800dp大于
the categories for all of these because 800 is greater than
720dp也大于600dp。但是系统会首先选择
720 and greater than 600. However, the system chooses the
最大限制的文件夹。所以这个item配置会被使用
most specific folder first. So it will choose this item layout
而不是这两个。因为detail配置没有在这里定义
over these two. Since the detail layout is not defined
系统会退回较小限制的文件夹，
here, it will fall back to a less specific folder, which
也就是这一个。然后是main.xml，它在这两个
is this one. Then for the main.xml file, it's not declared
文件夹里都没有被定义，所以系统会退回这一个
in either of these, so it falls back to this one.